hopperhq.com 2019-11-29

# Privacy - Hopper HQ Instagram Scheduler

Hopper HQ provides this Privacy Policy to inform users of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personally identifiable information received from users of this website, located at HopperHQ.com (“Site” ).

By using our Site you are consenting to our processing of your information as set forth in this Privacy Policy now and as amended by us. “Processing” means using cookies on a computer or using or touching information in any way, including, but not limited to, collecting, storing, deleting, using, combining and disclosing information. The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. Our current hosting providers are signed up to Privacy Shield.

By visiting our Site and providing information to us, you consent to such transfer to, and processing.

  * What information we collect about you
  * How we use information we collect 
  * How we share information we collect 
  * How we store and secure information we collect 
  * How to access and control your information 
  * Other important privacy information

### What information we collect about you

Our primary goals in collecting personally identifiable information are to provide you with the product and services made available through the Site, including, but not limited, to the Service, to communicate with you, and to manage your registered user account, if you have one.

##### **Site visitors:**

When someone visits www.hopperhq.com we use third party services, Google Analytics & Mixpanel, to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site and how those visitors arrived at the site. This information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make, and do not allow Google to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. If we do want to collect personally identifiable information through our website, we will be up front about this. We will make it clear when we collect personal information and will explain what we intend to do with it.

##### **Information Collected Upon Registration:**

If you desire to use the Hopper HQ web and mobile tools ( e.g. app.hopperhq.com) and want access to certain restricted sections of the Site, you will be required to become a registered user, and to submit certain personally identifiable information to Hopper HQ. This happens in a number of instances, such as when you sign up for the Service, or if you desire to receive marketing materials and information. Personally identifiable information that we may collect in such instances may include your IP address, full user name, password, email address, city, time zone, telephone number, and other information that you decide to provide us with.

##### **Use of Contact Information:**

In addition, we may use your contact information to market to you, and provide you with information about, our products and services, including but not limited to our Service. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such information or communications from us, please un-follow us, or follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications.

##### **Log Data:**

When you visit the Site, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website (“Log Data” ). This Log Data may include information such as your IP address, browser type or the domain from which you are visiting, the web-pages you visit, the search terms you use, and any advertisements on which you click. For most users accessing the Internet from an Internet service provider the IP address will be different every time you log on. We use Log Data to monitor the use of the Site and of our Service, and for the Site’s technical administration. We do not associate your IP address with any other personally identifiable information to identify you personally, except in case of violation of the Terms of Service.

##### **Cookies:**

Like many websites, we also use “cookie” technology to collect additional website usage data and to improve the Site and our service. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard disk. We do not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information. Hopper HQ may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to better understand how you interact with the Site and our Service, to monitor aggregate usage by our users and web traffic routing on the Site, and to improve the Site and our services. A session cookie enables certain features of the Site and our service and is deleted from your computer when you disconnect from or leave the Site. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser help file directions. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. You can instruct your browser, by editing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit

##### **Payment Information:**

When purchasing a paid membership we collect your billing information. This is done through our 3rd party billing service providers Stripe, ChartMogul & Stunning.

##### **Information you provide through our support channels:**

When contacting or using our customer support options, you may choose to submit information regarding a problem you are experiencing with a Service. Whether you open a support ticket via email, contact form, live chat or over the phone, you will be asked to provide contact information and a summary of the problem you are experiencing.  

##### **Newsletter & Email communication:**

We gather your email & statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies including clear gifs to help us monitor and improve our e-newsletter and email communications.

##### **Device and Connection Information:**

We collect information about your computer, phone, tablet, or other devices you use to access the Services. This device information includes your connection type and settings when you install, access, update, or use our Services. We also collect information through your device about your operating system, browser type, IP address, URLs of referring/exit pages, device identifiers, and crash data.

##### **Content you provide through using our products;**

We collect and store user generated content which you add when using our service. This include messages, posts, comments, pages, profiles, images and feeds for the social platforms you have connected to Hopper HQ.

##### Connected social media accounts

To post and mange to your social media platforms with Hopper HQ, we may ask you to provide your username, account ids, social handle, timezones, email address and password. On connecting a social account with Hopper HQ we may collect information from the account including profile images, display name, username / profile ID / account ID / page ID, access tokens, and historic posts. This includes the content of your post and engagement data (such as click rates, likes, comments, impressions, as well as general engagement counts), to the extent permitted by applicable law. This data will only be used by Hopper HQ to provide you with the Service you expect and will not be shared with any third parties.

### How we use information we collect

##### To provide the Services and personalise your experience

We use information about you to provide the Services to you, including to process transactions with you, authenticate you when you log in, provide customer support, post content to your connected social platforms, to provide you with analytics on your content’s performance and operate and maintain the Services.

##### For research and development

We are always looking for ways to make our Services smarter, faster, secure and useful to you. We use collective learnings about how people use our Services and feedback provided directly to us to troubleshoot and to identify trends, usage, activity patterns and areas for integration and improvement of the Services.

##### To communicate with you about the Services

We use your contact information to send transactional communications via email and within Hopper HQ, including confirming your purchases, reminding you of subscription expirations, responding to your comments, questions and requests, providing customer support, and sending you technical notices, updates, security alerts, administrative messages and upcoming event notifications. We send you email notifications when you or others interact with you on the Services, for example, when you are liked, added as a favourite, sent a card or messaged by another user. We also provide tailored communications based on your activity and interactions with us. These communications are part of the Services and in most cases you cannot opt out of them. If an opt out is available, you will find that option within the communication itself or in your account settings.

##### To market, promote and drive engagement with the Services

We use your contact information and information about how you use the Services to send promotional communications that may be of specific interest to you, including by email and by displaying Hopper HQ ads on other companies’ websites and applications, as well as on platforms like Facebook and Google. These communications are aimed at driving engagement and maximising what you get out of the Services, including information about new features, survey requests, newsletters, and events we think may be of interest to you. We also communicate with you about new product offers, promotions and contests. You can control whether you receive these communications in your Settings area.

##### Customer support

We use your information to resolve technical issues you may encounter and respond to requests for assistance.

##### For safety and security

We monitor and use your information to monitor suspicious activity, fraudulent, activity and reports of violations of our terms of service.

##### To protect our legitimate business interests and legal rights:

Where required by law or where we believe it is necessary to protect our legal rights, interests and the interests of others, we use information about you in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory, and audit functions, and disclosures in connection with the acquisition, merger or sale of a business.

##### With your consent:

We use information about you where you have given us consent to do so for a specific purpose not listed above. For example, we may publish testimonials or featured customer stories to promote the Services, with your permission.

##### **Legal basis for processing:  **

We collect and process information about you only where we have legal basis for doing so under applicable EU laws. The legal basis depend on the Services you use and how you use them. This means we collect and use your information only where:

  * We need it to provide you the Services, including to operate the Services, provide customer support and personalised features and to protect the safety and security of the Services;
  * It satisfies a legitimate interest (which is not overridden by your data protection interests), such as for research and development, to market and promote the Services and to protect our legal rights and interests;
  * You give us consent to do so for a specific purpose; or
  * We need to process your data to comply with a legal obligation.

If you have consented to our use of information about you for a specific purpose, you have the right to change your mind at any time, but this will not affect any processing that has already taken place. Where we are using your information because we or a third party (e.g. your employer) have a legitimate interest to do so, you have the right to object to that use though, in some cases, this may mean no longer using the Services.

### How we share information we collect

##### **Social Media Platforms**

Hopper HQ helps you plan, publish and analyse content on you social platforms. You can connect Hopper HQ to social platforms like Instagram and Facebook. In order to provide the Service we may transfer data to and from the third party social platforms. Content shared via Hopper HQ to social platforms will be governed by that platform’s privacy policy.

##### Service Providers:

We engage certain trusted third parties to perform functions and provide services to us, including, without limitation, hosting and maintenance, billing, customer relationship, database storage and management, and direct marketing campaigns. We will share your personally identifiable information with these third parties, but only to the extent necessary to perform these functions and provide such services, and only pursuant to binding contractual obligations requiring such third parties to maintain the privacy and security of your data.

##### **Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement:**

Hopper HQ cooperates with government and law enforcement officials or private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We may disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims, legal process (including subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of Hopper HQ or a third party, the safety of the public or any person, to prevent or stop any illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity, or to comply with the law.

##### **Business Transfers:**

Hopper HQ may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your personally identifiable information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganisation or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy. You will have the opportunity to opt out of any such transfer if the new entity’s planned processing of your information differs materially from that set forth in this Privacy Policy.

##### **Links to Other Websites:**

Our Site contains links to other websites. The fact that we link to a website is not an endorsement, authorisation or representation of our affiliation with that third party. We do not exercise control over third party websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personally identifiable information from you. Other sites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personally identifiable information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

##### **Third-Party Widgets:  **

Some of our Services contain widgets and social media features, such as the Twitter “tweet” button. These widgets and features collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on the Services, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Widgets and social media features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Services. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

##### **With your consent:**

We share information about you with third parties when you give us consent to do so.  For example, we often display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our public websites. With your consent, we may post your name alongside the testimonial.

### How we store and secure information we collect

##### Information storage and security

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. Our current hosting providers are signed up to Privacy Shield.

##### **Security**

Hopper HQ is very concerned about safeguarding the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information. We employ administrative, physical and electronic measures designed to protect your information from unauthorised access. We will make any legally-required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored personal data to you via email or conspicuous posting on this Site in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system.

##### How long we keep information:

How long we keep information we collect about you depends on the type of information, as described in further detail below.  After such time, we will either delete or anonymise your information or, if this is not possible (for example, because the information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your information and isolate it from any further use until deletion is possible.

###### Hopper HQ account information:

We retain your account information until you permanently delete your account or you request that we remove the data.

###### Social account information & historic posts:

When you delete a social profile from your Hopper HQ account all user generated content such as posts are deleted from Hopper HQ. They will however remain on the respective social networks if the posts have already been published.

###### **Marketing information:  **

If you have elected to receive marketing emails from us, we retain information about your marketing preferences unless you specifically ask us to delete such information. We retain information derived from cookies and other tracking technologies for a reasonable period of time from the date such information was created.

### How to access and control your information

##### **Changing or Deleting Information**

If you are a registered user of the Site, you may access and update, correct or delete the information you provided to us in your account settings area or by e-mailing us at support@HopperHQ.com.

##### **Deleting a social account from Hopper HQ:  **

When you choose to remove one of your connected social accounts from Hopper HQ it is permanently removed from our service. All user generated and historic content is removed from Hopper HQ, this is non reversible. Any content posted via Hopper HQ to a 3rd party network (such as Instagram, Facebook or Twitter) will remain on their services.

##### **Request that we stop using your information:**

In some cases, you may ask us to stop accessing, storing, using and otherwise processing your information where you believe we don’t have the appropriate rights to do so.  For example, if you believe a Services account was created for you without your permission or you are no longer an active user, you can request that we delete your account as provided in this policy.  Where you gave us consent to use your information for a limited purpose, you can contact us to withdraw that consent, but this will not affect any processing that has already taken place at the time. When you make such requests, we may need time to investigate and facilitate your request.

##### **Opt out of communications:**

Each email sent by Hopper HQ contains an unsubscribe link to stop future emails of that kind. You can update you email notification preferences & email communication preferences in the settings area of your Hopper HQ account. You can also opt-out of our use of your information for marketing purposes by contacting us.  Some communications are part of the Services you cannot opt out of them and continue to use the services. In this scenario you can opt out of the communications by deactivating your account.

##### **Data portability:  **

Data portability is the ability to obtain some of your information in a format you can move from one service provider to another (for instance, when you transfer your mobile phone number to another carrier). Depending on the context, this applies to some of your information, but not to all of your information. Should you request it, we will provide you with an electronic file of your account information.

### Other important privacy information

##### **Our Policy Towards Children**

The Site is not directed to persons under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with personally identifiable information without their consent, he or she should contact us at support@HopperHQ.com. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal identifiable Information, we will delete such information from our files.

##### **Changes to this Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time for any reason; each version will apply to information collected while it was in place. We will notify you of any material changes to our Privacy Policy by posting the new Privacy Policy on our Site. You are advised to consult this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes.

### Contact Us

Your information is controlled by Hopper HQ Ltd. If you have questions or concerns about how your information is handled, please direct your inquiry to Hopper HQ Ltd, as set forth below.

Hopper HQ Ltd  
Innovation Birmingham,  
Holt Street,  
Birmingham,  
West Midlands,  
B7 4BB  

This Privacy Policy is effective as of May 25, 2018
